import shuffle from "../../../utils/GroovyShuffle";
import { QuestionType } from "./../StandardGame";

export const religionyear9qs: QuestionType[] = shuffle([
  {
    question: "What word is used to describe all that God has made?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(CREATION)",
    help: "Creation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What Belgian priest came up with a theory how the universe began?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(GEORGE)ANDCONTAINSOR(LEMAITRE_LEMAÎTRE)",
    help: "Fr Georges Lemaître",
  },
  {
    question: "Lemaître believed _______ and religion complemented each other?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(SCIENCE)",
    help: "Science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the theory of billions of years ago a massive explosion happened?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(BIG)ANDCONTAINS(BANG)",
    help: "The Big Bang Theory",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the intelligent designer?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(GOD)",
    help: "God, the universe is so well put together proves that God existed",
  },
  {
    question: "What is William Paley's watch theory?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(COMPL)",
    help: "Complicated watch pieces fit together. The universe is more complex and must have had a maker. The universe proves God exists",
  },
  {
    question: "1. God said 'Let there be _____'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(LIGHT)",
    help: "Light",
  },
  {
    question: "2. God said 'Let there be a dome in the _______'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(HEAVENS)",
    help: "Heavens",
  },
  {
    question:
      "3. God said 'Let the waters be gathered together and let ___ land appear'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(DRY)",
    help: "Dry",
  },
  {
    question:
      "4. God said 'Let there be lights in the sky to shine ___ and night'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(DAY)",
    help: "Day",
  },
  {
    question:
      "5. God said 'Let there be water filled with every kind of living thing, and air filled with _____'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(BIRDS)",
    help: "Birds",
  },
  {
    question:
      "6. God said 'Let the Earth be filled with every kind of ______'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(ANIMAL)",
    help: "Animal",
  },
  {
    question:
      "7. God said 'Let there be men and women and ________ in my own image and likeness'?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(CHILDREN)",
    help: "Children",
  },
  {
    question: "On the seventh day God ______?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(RESTED)",
    help: "Rested",
  },
  {
    question: "God blessed the seventh day and made it ____?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(HOLY)",
    help: "Holy",
  },
]);
